<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Education Skills Hub</title>
    <link href="https://edskills.org/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://edskills.org" />
    <updated>2025-10-20T13:54:50-05:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>EdSkills Hub</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://edskills.org</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Digital STARs</title>
        <author>
            <name>EdSkills Hub</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://edskills.org/digital-stars/"/>
        <id>https://edskills.org/digital-stars/</id>
        <media:content url="https://edskills.org/media/posts/10/imagen_v2.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Tools"/>

        <updated>2025-10-03T10:28:11-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://edskills.org/media/posts/10/imagen_v2.png" alt="Digital STARs" />
                    The Digital STARs Program is the World Bank’s flagship initiative to close the digital divide in Romania. By 2026, it will train 100,000 citizens in basic digital skills, turning public libraries into community learning hubs. The program combines a life-centered curriculum, a blended learning model, and a nationwide training-of-trainers cascade&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://edskills.org/media/posts/10/imagen_v2.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Digital STARs" /></p>
                <p>The Digital STARs Program is the World Bank’s flagship initiative to close the digital divide in Romania. By 2026, it will train 100,000 citizens in basic digital skills, turning public libraries into community learning hubs. The program combines a life-centered curriculum, a blended learning model, and a nationwide training-of-trainers cascade to ensure no one is left behind in the digital transition.</p>
<div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9CPmQm2IdhE?cc_load_policy=1&amp;cc_lang_pref=en&amp;hl=en" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></div>
<h3><strong>Who this tool is for</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li class="p1">Citizens with little or no digital skills, including women, youth, Roma, rural residents, pensioners, and the unemployed.</li>
<li>Librarians and local facilitators who deliver training as community mentors.</li>
<li>Schools, ministries, and NGOs seeking scalable models for digital inclusion.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>What you get</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li class="p1"><strong>Digital Skills Training:</strong> A 60-hour blended course aligned with Romania’s new DigCompRo framework, covering six key competence areas and 23 skills.</li>
<li><strong>Life-centered curriculum:</strong> Three tracks – <em>Personal Life, Civic Life, Professional Life</em> – ensure skills are applied in everyday contexts.</li>
<li><strong>Training-of-Trainers (ToT):</strong> A cascade model (20 master trainers → 700 librarians → 100,000 citizens) that empowers local mentors.</li>
<li><strong>Modernized libraries:</strong> Over 1,100 libraries equipped with high-speed internet, computers, and trained staff as digital hubs.</li>
<li><strong>Learning platform:</strong> A dedicated LMS with self-reflection tools, activities, and online resources to support hybrid learning.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>How to use it</strong></h3>
<ol class="ordered-list">
<li class="p1">Select and train librarians through the ToT program.</li>
<li>Enroll citizens through public libraries and community outreach campaigns.</li>
<li>Deliver the 60-hour blended course (online + in-person), applying modules to daily life events.</li>
<li>Support learners with mentoring, hands-on practice, and peer-to-peer interaction.</li>
<li>Monitor progress using built-in assessments and DigCompRo-based self-reflection questions.</li>
</ol>
<p><a href="https://edskills.org/how-to-guide-digital-stars/">For more detail, view the <em>how-to guide</em> for this program.</a></p>
<h3><strong>Time and effort</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li class="p1">Setup: Train master trainers and librarians (Nov 2024–Apr 2025).</li>
<li>Instruction: Citizens complete 60 hours of training, paced flexibly across 2–3 months.</li>
<li>Support: Ongoing mentoring, coaching for librarians, and national webinars through June 2026.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Languages</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li class="p1">Available in <strong>Romanian</strong>.</li>
<li>Adaptable to other languages with translation and localization.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Evidence and impact</strong></h3>
<p class="p3">Romania ranks last in the EU in basic digital skills (28% vs. 54% EU average). Adult participation in lifelong learning is also the lowest in the EU (4.9%). Digital STARs directly addresses this gap by equipping citizens with essential skills for personal, civic, and professional life. The program is part of Romania’s National Recovery and Resilience Plan (PNRR), modernizing libraries in all 42 counties and strengthening employability, e-government use, and social inclusion. <br><br>Its scalable design makes it a model for other countries facing similar challenges.</p>
<p><a href="https://edskills.org/evidence-digital-stars/">For more detail, view the <em>evidence and case studies</em> page for this program.</a></p>
<h3><strong>Program screenshots</strong></h3>
<div class="gallery-wrapper"><div class="gallery"  data-is-empty="false" data-translation="Add images" data-columns="3">
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://edskills.org/media/posts/10/gallery/Screenshot-2025-10-09-at-12.45.49.png" data-size="1276x985"><img loading="lazy" src="https://edskills.org/media/posts/10/gallery/Screenshot-2025-10-09-at-12.45.49-thumbnail.png" alt="Digital STARs Moodle screenshot" width="768" height="593"></a>
<figcaption>Digital STARs Moodle screenshot</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://edskills.org/media/posts/10/gallery/Screenshot-2025-10-09-at-12.45.40.png" data-size="1276x985"><img loading="lazy" src="https://edskills.org/media/posts/10/gallery/Screenshot-2025-10-09-at-12.45.40-thumbnail.png" alt="Digital STARs Moodle screenshot" width="768" height="593"></a>
<figcaption>Digital STARs Moodle screenshot</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://edskills.org/media/posts/10/gallery/Screenshot-2025-10-09-at-12.45.27.png" data-size="1276x985"><img loading="lazy" src="https://edskills.org/media/posts/10/gallery/Screenshot-2025-10-09-at-12.45.27-thumbnail.png" alt="Digital STARs Moodle screenshot - pretest" width="768" height="593"></a>
<figcaption>Digital STARs Moodle screenshot - pretest</figcaption>
</figure>
</div></div>
<h3><strong>Downloads and links</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Course demo</strong>: <a href="https://digitalstars.neting.hu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Access here</a><br>(Username: <code>wb_student</code>, Password: <code>DigitalStars2025!</code>)</li>
<li><a href="https://edskills.org/media/files/Digital STARs_one pager_v2.pdf">Program overview (PDF)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://edskills.org/RAS Digital Skills_final presentation.pdf">Romania Digital Skills RAS presentation (PDF)</a>: Maximizing the uptake, outcomes and benefits stemming from the digital economy</li>
<li>Librarian training handbooks – <i>coming soon</i></li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Contact</strong></h3>
<p class="p3">For more information or to adapt this program in your country, contact:</p>
<p><strong>Alina Sava</strong> – <i>Senior Education Specialist, World Bank</i><br><a href="mailto:asava@worldbank.org">asava@worldbank.org</a></p>
<p><strong>Cristóbal Cobo</strong> – <i>Senior Education Specialist, World Bank</i><br><a href="mailto:ccobo@worldbank.org">ccobo@worldbank.org</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Teach RO</title>
        <author>
            <name>EdSkills Hub</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://edskills.org/teach-romania/"/>
        <id>https://edskills.org/teach-romania/</id>
        <media:content url="https://edskills.org/media/posts/5/ro2.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Tools"/>

        <updated>2025-09-08T11:38:52-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://edskills.org/media/posts/5/ro2.png" alt="Learning socio-emotional skills" />
                    Note: These resources are currently available in the Romanian language. TEACH is the World Bank’s classroom observation tool used worldwide to measure teaching practices and support professional development. It focuses on how teachers manage the classroom, deliver instruction, and engage students. By providing a structured framework for observation, TEACH helps&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://edskills.org/media/posts/5/ro2.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Learning socio-emotional skills" /></p>
                <p class="msg msg--warning"><em>Note</em>: These resources are currently available in the Romanian language.</p>
<p class="p1"><a href="https://www.worldbank.org/en/topic/education/brief/teach-helping-countries-track-and-improve-teaching-quality"><strong>TEACH</strong></a> is the World Bank’s classroom observation tool used worldwide to measure teaching practices and support professional development. It focuses on how teachers manage the classroom, deliver instruction, and engage students. By providing a structured framework for observation, TEACH helps generate feedback that improves the quality of teaching.</p>
<p class="p1"><strong><a href="https://teach.edu.ro">Teach RO</a></strong> offers a practical tool and course for observing teaching in <span class="s1"><strong>primary and preschool</strong></span> classrooms in Romania. The course focuses on core domains such as <span class="s1"><strong>classroom climate</strong></span> and <span class="s1"><strong>instruction</strong></span>, and is delivered on the Teach RO platform (<a href="https://teach.edu.ro">teach.edu.ro</a>).</p>
<p class="p1">In Romania, TEACH has been adapted into a four-module e-learning program (plus introduction and evaluation) that goes beyond observation to actively train teachers. The modules combine international best practices with local classroom examples, equipping educators with strategies for effective instruction, positive classroom management, and stronger student engagement. This version offers Romanian teachers both the global rigor of TEACH and practical, context-specific support for improving their daily practice.</p>
<h3><strong>Who it’s for</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li class="p1">Teachers and school leaders in primary or preschool education</li>
<li>Methodologists, mentors, and inspectors who conduct classroom observations</li>
<li class="p1">Faculties of education and NGOs supporting early-years and primary pedagogy</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>What you learn</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li class="p1">How to use a structured observation framework in real classrooms</li>
<li>How to document evidence on classroom climate and instructional practices</li>
<li>How to give clear, actionable feedback to teachers based on observed behaviors</li>
<li>How to support socio-emotional skills alongside classroom climate and instruction</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="p1"><strong>Format</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li class="p1">Online access via the <a href="https://teach.edu.ro">Teach RO platform</a></li>
<li class="p1">Course content is organized around observation domains (climate, instruction, socio-emotional skills) and includes guided note-taking, coding practice, quizzes, and exemplars, plus a synchronous element</li>
<li>Includes guidance, examples, and tools for use during live lessons</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="p1"><strong>How to enroll</strong></h3>
<p class="p2">The live course is available at: <span class="s1"><strong><a href="https://teach.edu.ro/courses/teach-ro/">teach.edu.ro/courses/teach-ro</a></strong></span>. Access is provided on the Teach RO platform.</p>
<h3><strong>Time and effort</strong></h3>
<p class="p1">The Teach RO course is designed to fit educators’ real schedules. Most participants complete it over <strong><span class="s1">two to three weeks in a 40-hour training program</span></strong>, depending on how much classroom practice they choose to include.</p>
<ul>
<li class="p1">Each module can be completed independently.</li>
<li>Observation activities can be integrated into regular class hours.</li>
<li>The course requires only basic digital skills and internet access.</li>
</ul>
<p class="p1">The goal is to make professional reflection and feedback part of daily teaching, not an extra burden.</p>
<h3><strong>Languages</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li class="p1">Available in <span class="s1"><strong>Romanian</strong></span>.</li>
<li>Can be adapted for other countries (piloted in Armenia, Ukraine, Kosovo).</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Evidence and impact</strong></h3>
<figure class="post__video"><iframe loading="lazy" width="560" height="314" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9guYKZ2frnQ" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" data-mce-fragment="1"></iframe></figure>
<p>Teach has been piloted across several countries and is grounded in the World Bank’s global framework for measuring teaching practices. In Romania, it provides a scalable model for teacher training, reaching thousands of educators through online delivery. <span class="s1">Its indicators on </span><strong>classroom climate</strong><span class="s1"> and </span><strong>instructional quality</strong><span class="s1"> are used to:</span></p>
<ul>
<li class="p1"><span class="s1">Provide </span><strong>consistent, evidence-based feedback</strong><span class="s1"> to teachers.</span></li>
<li class="p1">Support <span class="s1"><strong>school improvement plans</strong></span> and teacher mentoring.</li>
<li class="p1">Build <span class="s1"><strong>national data</strong></span> on teaching quality and learning environments.</li>
</ul>
<p class="p4">Teachers and mentors who have applied the framework report clearer discussions about instruction, stronger professional trust, and visible improvement in student engagement.</p>
<h3><strong>Screenshots</strong></h3>
<div class="gallery-wrapper"><div class="gallery"  data-is-empty="false" data-translation="Add images" data-columns="3">
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://edskills.org/media/posts/5/gallery/Screenshot-2025-10-20-at-13.29.36.png" data-size="1390x1105"><img loading="lazy" src="https://edskills.org/media/posts/5/gallery/Screenshot-2025-10-20-at-13.29.36-thumbnail.png" alt="Screenshot from Teach RO online course" width="768" height="611"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://edskills.org/media/posts/5/gallery/Screenshot-2025-10-20-at-13.29.54.png" data-size="1390x1105"><img loading="lazy" src="https://edskills.org/media/posts/5/gallery/Screenshot-2025-10-20-at-13.29.54-thumbnail.png" alt="Screenshot from Teach RO online course" width="768" height="611"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://edskills.org/media/posts/5/gallery/Screenshot-2025-10-20-at-13.30.23.png" data-size="1390x1105"><img loading="lazy" src="https://edskills.org/media/posts/5/gallery/Screenshot-2025-10-20-at-13.30.23-thumbnail.png" alt="Screenshot from Teach RO online course" width="768" height="611"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://edskills.org/media/posts/5/gallery/Screenshot-2025-10-20-at-13.29.15.png" data-size="1390x1105"><img loading="lazy" src="https://edskills.org/media/posts/5/gallery/Screenshot-2025-10-20-at-13.29.15-thumbnail.png" alt="Screenshot from Teach RO online course" width="768" height="611"></a></figure>
</div></div>
<h3><strong>Links</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li class="p1"><span style="font-size: inherit;"><a href="https://teach.edu.ro">Teach RO</a></span></li>
<li><a href="https://teach.edu.ro/courses/teach-ro/">Teach RO course</a></li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Contact</strong></h3>
<p class="p3">For more information or to bring Teach RO to your country, contact:</p>
<p><span class="s1"><strong>Alina Sava</strong></span> – <i>Senior Education Specialist, World Bank<br></i><a href="mailto:asava@worldbank.org">asava@worldbank.org</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Remedial Math Program</title>
        <author>
            <name>EdSkills Hub</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://edskills.org/remedial-math-program/"/>
        <id>https://edskills.org/remedial-math-program/</id>
        <media:content url="https://edskills.org/media/posts/4/RO1.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Tools"/>

        <updated>2025-09-08T11:23:47-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://edskills.org/media/posts/4/RO1.png" alt="Image depicting graph paper, geometric shapes, and a compass" />
                    Note: These resources are currently available in the Romanian language. The Remedial Math Program gives students who are falling behind a second chance to succeed. Built in Romania and piloted in vulnerable schools, it combines teacher support, engaging digital lessons, and diagnostic assessments. The program targets middle- and lower-secondary students&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://edskills.org/media/posts/4/RO1.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Image depicting graph paper, geometric shapes, and a compass" /></p>
                <p class="msg msg--warning"><em>Note</em>: These resources are currently available in the Romanian language.</p>
<p>The Remedial Math Program gives students who are falling behind a second chance to succeed. Built in Romania and piloted in vulnerable schools, it combines teacher support, engaging digital lessons, and diagnostic assessments. The program targets middle- and lower-secondary students (grades 5–8) as well as those entering high school with weak math foundations, and helps them build essential skills step by step.</p>
<h3><strong>Who this tool is for</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li class="p1">Students at risk of dropping out or underperforming in math, especially in grades 5–8.</li>
<li>Teachers working in rural and underserved schools.</li>
<li>Schools and ministries looking for scalable, low-cost remedial solutions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>What you get</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li class="p1"><span class="s1"><strong>Foundational Teaching Skills (AFP modules):</strong></span> Eleven core skills for effective classroom practice, aligned with the World Bank’s TEACH framework. These include checking for understanding, feedback, adaptation, and building positive classroom climate.</li>
<li class="p1"><span class="s1"><strong>Student learning units:</strong></span> Ten structured units delivered over 30 weeks (approx. 45 hours), covering numbers, algebra, geometry, and data &amp; probability. Each unit blends short theory blocks, guided practice, and quick checks for understanding.</li>
<li class="p1"><span class="s1"><strong>Lesson skeleton and tutorials:</strong></span> Consistent templates that link diagnostics (e.g., BRIO) to instruction, ensuring every session follows a predictable, student-centered routine.</li>
<li class="p1"><span class="s1"><strong>Diagnostic tool:</strong></span> Baseline and follow-up assessments (e.g., BRIO tests) that identify learning gaps from grades 5–8 and track progress.</li>
<li class="p1"><span class="s1"><strong>Teacher resource kits:</strong></span> Guides, examples, and AI-supported materials to help teachers plan and deliver lessons effectively.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>How to use it</strong></h3>
<ol class="ordered-list">
<li class="p1">Run the diagnostic test to identify student needs and group them by skill gaps.</li>
<li>Deliver the 10 learning units across 30 weeks (1.5–2 hours per week), using the lesson skeleton as your guide.</li>
<li>Use the digital tutorials and the Relu avatar to demonstrate concepts and keep students engaged.</li>
<li>Monitor progress with built-in assessments at the end of each unit, and regroup students when needed.</li>
<li>Join webinars and training sessions to strengthen teacher practice and share experiences.</li>
</ol>
<p><a href="https://edskills.org/how-to-guide-remedial-math-program/">For more detail, view the "how-to" guide for this program.</a></p>
<h3><strong>Time and effort</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li class="p1">Setup: Install program container on school servers or computers.</li>
<li>Instruction: 30 weeks of learning (approx. 45 hours total).</li>
<li>Support: 8 webinars offered during rollout.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Languages</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li class="p1">Available in <span class="s1"><strong>Romanian</strong></span>.</li>
<li>Adaptable to other languages with translation and subtitles.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Evidence and impact</strong></h3>
<p class="p3">Piloted in Romania under the PNRAS program, the Remedial Math Program directly addresses the skill gaps identified by national diagnostics and World Bank TEACH classroom observations. <br><br>BRIO assessments show that students struggle most with real numbers, data/graph interpretation, and early algebra. Teach classroom data highlight areas such as feedback, deeper thinking, and student collaboration. The program is designed to close these gaps through targeted instruction and consistent teaching practices. <br><br>Early results show that low-performing students can progress toward average performance levels, offering a more inclusive pathway through secondary education and reducing the need for private tutoring.</p>
<p>For detailed findings, see our <a href="https://edskills.org/evidence-remedial-math-program/">Evidence &amp; Case Studies</a> post.</p>
<h3><strong>Demonstration</strong></h3>
<p class="p3"><i>(Coming soon.)</i></p>
<h3><strong>Downloads and links</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://edskills.org/Early Grade Mathematics Toolkit-Initiating Dialogue on Early Mathematics_.pdf">Presentation: Early Grade Mathematics Toolkit-Initiating Dialogue on Early Mathematics (PDF)</a></li>
<li class="p1">Program container (zip package) – <i>coming soon</i></li>
<li>Teacher handbooks and resource kits – <i>coming soon</i></li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Contact</strong></h3>
<p class="p3">For more information or to adapt this program in your country, contact:</p>
<p><span class="s1"><strong>Alina Sava</strong></span> – <i>Senior Education Specialist, World Bank<br></i><a href="mailto:asava@worldbank.org">asava@worldbank.org</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
